I think most of what's driving crypto
right now is a combination of new
players coming in. This is what a bull
market is about. And you're right, FOMO
is going to start to kick in very, very
soon. I said before when Bitcoin got
above 82,000, that was the confirmation
[music] of the bull trend. I think we're
in that. The fundamental side's getting
stronger and stronger by the day. I I
think we're at a point where this stuff
is about to [music] kind of take off,
particularly with what happened today
with the What's going on, guys? Today,
we got a great conversation with Jordy
Visser. In this one, we're going to talk
about what's going on in the macro
world. Why are people so fearful when
the data actually says you should be
bullish? What's going on in AI? Why is
the rise of personal AI assistance very
bullish for token consumption or the big
model labs actually coming under
pressure or not? Jord and I disagree and
then we agree on a big topic that I
think you're going to enjoy. And then we
talk about crypto, public equities, and
what he sees going on in people's
portfolios, how the end of the year
should go, where we're going next year,
and maybe he even gives a little bit of
alpha, something he calls the micron
moment, which I think that all of you
will be very interested in. Here's my
latest conversation with Jordi Visser.
All right, Jordy, it seems like every
single person I talk to from the
traditional world, they are freaking out
about macro factors. They're saying
interest rates are going up, oil's at
100, the 10-year keeps going higher.
They are so worried that the big crash,
the Michael Bur moment is coming. I
don't get the sense that you agree.
I actually think it's stupid.
Podcast over. I I mean, I've posted an X
a bunch about this this week. I did a
subscriber video and I had like 25
slides of of why this is just add it to
the list of doomer stuff that comes out.
uh tariffs and the war and oil's going
to infinity and all of these things. So
this is the way the economy works.
We have a very diverse economy in the
US. We have a diverse stock market.
Theoretically, we have 500 names in the
S&P 500.
Rates mattered a lot before the great
financial crisis. They mattered a lot
into the great financial crisis because
the economy was built on autos, housing.
Um that's why we created things like the
leading economic indicators. We have
what's called financial conditions
index. Everything changed after the
great financial crisis. So the first
thing about rates are everyone's like
we're at 20-year highs for rates. Well,
let's just go back to what that means.
That means by definition rates just
before the great financial crisis. I'm
not sure anyone got the memo, but to
save us from the great financial crisis,
they had to move rates to zero and then
we stayed at zero for a long time to get
us out of the problem. So really what's
happened to rates is they've normalized.
Nominal GDP is six and change percent.
Historically 10ear rates should be 200
basis points above. Now let's say it's
about it. That changed in 1997. So let's
say it just goes to even. We're still
cheap relative to nominal GDP. Now, that
matters because GDP is growing at six
and a half percent. Theoretically, if
you just take what that is, that means
you'd have to have rates above it to
where it would be difficult to make
money if that's kind of how much money
you can make investing wise or
transaction-wise, business-wise.
>> But that's not the case. So, with inside
the S&P 500 are a lot of zombie
companies. I mean, I hate to say it, but
home builders don't make much money
these days. Auto companies, Ford, GM,
>> is that stuff just interest rate driven,
or do you think that is like a
structural change in the market and home
builders, as an example, are going to
have a tough time for the next 20 years?
>> I think home builders are going to have
a tough time for ever. Um, I think the
economy is changing. I think
demographics are changing. I think the
way people view um mobilization having
the flexibility of moving from state to
state, country to country, that's been a
change with the younger generation for
some time. The old I go to college, I
get a job, I buy a house after I, you
know, I have kids and then I stay there
for 30, 40 years. That doesn't exist
anymore. And so, we don't have enough
housing in the country. So, do I think
there'll be more apartments and things
like that? Yeah. Do I think Airbnb will
be? Yeah, I think all of those things
will happen. But to compare the economy,
and this is the best way to do it, and
this is what I'm including in this
week's video. If you take the revenue
for Micron and Nvidia in 2015, so 11
years ago,
>> and you compare that to Ford, GM, and
the Homebuilders,
you're talking about Ford, GM, and the
Homebuilders being like almost 20 times
the size of the annual revenue for
Micron, Nvidia. And now you fast
forward, Micron and Nvidia alone have
more than those those the homebuilders
plus Ford and and GM. But even worse
than that,
the expectations of revenue growth for
the next year for Nvidia are almost the
entire size of the revenue that will be
generated. We just have a completely
different economy. And so when people
roll this stuff out, once it starts
with, oh, every time this has happened
over the past 50 years, X happens. This
is not the same economy. And I'll just
as as both being sports fans, they
changed the rules in the NFL. You know,
you used to be able to use stick them on
your hands to, you know, grab intercept
the ball. You could hold on to someone,
you wouldn't let go. A lot of different
rules. You can't touch anyone in the NFL
anymore. You can't touch the
quarterback. Is it fair to compare stats
of the 1970s and 80s to today? Of course
not. But somehow or another, macro
people that are in their 50s that never
touch AI, and that's my big beef is that
if you actually used AI and you saw
where things were going, you actually
saw the productivity gains, you'd
recognize that the economy's changed. So
that's why whether it's oil, whether
it's rates, it's not the same economy as
before 2007. And that's because of the
iPhone.
>> Do are you aware of any measurement that
basically looks at uh sector-based
dollar flows? So like, you know, there's
capital flows. people pay attention to
macro in terms of uh liquidity cycles
and things like that. But it's a very
interesting way to think about okay how
much aggregate dollars are going towards
home builders and the revenue and profit
that's growing there versus maybe some
of these other sectors and and the
reason I immediately am intrigued by
that is it's not just that oh Micron and
Nvidia were low and now they're high.
It's that they're actually accelerating.
And so if you look at this not as a
static thing but a dynamic trend they
should pull away very aggressively here
and then the question becomes okay well
what are the sectors that are getting
hammered you mentioned housing and car
manufacturing but I don't know I could
probably think of very quickly 10 or 12
you know different types of businesses
that are all going to be in somewhat of
a static you know um kind of environment
going forward
>> I mean there's a huge opportunity to
just take capital out of those sectors
>> Yep. and rotate them over and almost
indiscriminate of names. It is just
literally where is the momentum and
growth coming from
like a Buffett style approach. I don't
think that buying things for less than
they're worth is ever going to go out of
style, but just like buying quote
unquote good, strong, cash flowing
businesses feels like that type of value
investor may have a tough time going
forward.
>> So, let's go back to 2015. So, the other
thing that I did is, and let's take it
back to the iPhone. So, when the iPhone,
believe it or not, when the iPhone came
out, remember that was at the end of a
7-year bare market in technology. So, we
had the dot bubble and it took 7 years
all the way into the great financial
crisis to basically get back to where we
were at that time. Technology
was about 13% of the S&P 500. And this
is where your question on revenue so
people understand you can have a lot of
revenue in a sector but if it's not
growing the S&P 500 is not going to
value it but S&P 500 does care about the
revenues but it cares about the growth
and right now the S&P 500 if you take
technology sector which is going to
include software and semis you add in
basically companies like Netflix and uh
Google and Meta and Amazon and Tesla
because they're technology companies,
but they're in other sectors. You're up
to 56% of the S&P 500 now. 56. Wow.
>> So, we've already hurt all of these
others. This is what gets into the other
thing people are talking about. So,
>> there's this new highs, new lows, and
the breath. The breath is horrible.
Okay, let's go through what this means.
If seven companies are winning and the
tech side is now 56%. Whenever tech is
dominating, these companies are the
breath is going to be bad by definition.
But if you move rates higher, tech is
insensitive to rates. And this is the
other mistake people are making. Now,
the doomers will tell you that, "Oh my
god, we need capital and this is
borrowing money." And I've said
repeatedly on everything I speak at,
there is absolutely no sensitivity for
rates in the AI trade. None. You can
move it up a lot. If compute prices
don't come down, Nvidia, it just doesn't
matter. I mean, I know it's hard for
people to believe that, but the reality
is the margins for Micron, they just
released earnings this week, 87%.
There is so much margin in what
Anthropic does and what OpenAI does that
they're selling compute at prices
because people need it. It's
intelligence. It's incredible. They need
it.
>> I may disagree with some of this.
>> Okay. Well, let's let's finish the the
statement first. So when you look at
newo new highs and new lows and everyone
goes look at all the new lows. You know
what the new lows are in? Consumer
staples.
>> True.
>> Utilities, real estate, you know what
those names are? They're all interest
rate sensitive. They all they have no
benefit from the AI situation cuz AI is
driving rates higher. It's hurting these
groups. And that's why they're trading
at 52- week lows because who wants to
own a consumer staples and a utility
when they're basically just synthetic
bond positions when bond rates are going
higher?
I agree that the rate sensitive
businesses 100% are under pressure,
going to be under pressure until things
change. Anyone who disagrees with that,
I think that that's actually a uh
agreement point between the like doomers
and the AI folks is there's a certain
part of the economy if rates go up,
they're going to get hurt on tech, the
individual businesses, I agree. I do
think though there's a connection
between rates going up and the top in
November of 2021 as an example. So the
Fed comes out and says, "Hey, we are
going to start raising rates." They
don't do it till March of 22, but that
pretty much marked the top. If you go
back to 200 uh 2000 kind of bubble,
right? Same thing. Rates, they kind of
forecast, hey, we're going to raise
rates, market turns over. So in a weird
way, it doesn't impact the actual
businesses, but on an overall like
almost macro basis, when they say
they're going to raise rates, usually
that has marked some sort of top, which
I think is what the doomers are kind of
pulling back to. I think your point it
sounds like is well rates are going up
right now and the market is going up too
which kind of like violates that that
viewpoint. So put that aside for one
second. I am um I went from anthropic
open AI etc being the best businesses in
the world to now I think I'm in the camp
of there's an increasing chance that
they are going to be way underperform
what people think and there are three
data points I'd love your reaction to.
First is token consumption per customer
seems to have exploded and now is
starting to turn over in a number of
things. We see this in the ramp AI index
spending is down. We also see this in a
number of these kind of metrics that
look at you know whether it's open
router or whatever that that that's
coming down. We also know uh Grock
recently released their latest uh model
and they showed a chart of performance
and price. Everything is getting better
performance and price is coming down. So
it looks like everything's kind of
diving down into the right. Well, if you
take those two numbers, number of tokens
processed times price of token, that is
ultimately the revenue of the model
labs. So talking to Dan Ives this week
and I said, look, if those two numbers
are both coming down
anthropic, like the latest charts are
just kind of showing slight growth, but
to like plateau revenue. And so as
businesses realize like maybe we need to
own more of this ourselves and not just
outsource everything to these two
companies. It feels like there's some
pressure there. Now the overall market
is growing maybe there's like breath in
AI where like the revenue flows but
could there be weakness in the model
labs and maybe some pressure of them get
actually getting public yet the AI trade
more broadly continues and so like
you're almost getting like a
reallocation of where value is acrewing.
>> So let me I'm going to disagree with a
lot of what you said. Yes,
>> but not the facts. Okay,
>> so the the things you highlighted.
>> Oh, great. Just call me dumb. [laughter]
>> No, but you're falling into the trap of
uh that most people get into, which is
well, let's look at this data. Let's go
through. So, let's let's
>> save me, Jordy. No, when So, the first
part of this year was about token
maxing. Let's just throw tons of tokens
inefficiently at everything and see what
happens.
>> Okay. Well, we knew that was going to
end. So, when you look at the ramp index
and all this stuff,
>> the token cost will is deflationary.
It's going to continue to come down.
There's models now that 3 months ago
from I mean even even open AI has the
models from 3 months ago which are
better today than 3 months ago are
cheaper than they were back then. So
everything is moving that way. So let's
leave that alone.
>> We've entered the agentic side.
>> Mhm.
>> The token numbers are going to explode.
>> We are going to see So all we had were
enterprise agents.
>> Mhm. 8 billion people on the planet
didn't use anything. Well, now Grock,
Instinct, Muse are just starting.
>> But how many of those So this is where I
think the nuance is. How many of those
use OpenAI or anthropic models?
>> Well, no, no, no. Not so let me get to
the end because there let's go what you
said at the beginning. I am not some
bull on open AI and anthropic. But
>> are you a bear?
>> No. At the But here's the thing. Do I
think their growth rate has already
passed the fastest point? Absolutely. So
the conversation remember two months ago
was they're they're on an annualized run
rate which is still there philanthropic
of 100 plus billion. Okay.
>> Nice business. Like by the way I'm not
uh I'm not saying I'm not jealous of
having that business.
>> Let's just get something straight for
everyone who's like wants to fade these
guys. The total revenue for this year
that OpenAI and Anthropic will have at
the end of this year will be greater
than the entire software revenue. So
let's let's just get something straight
like these are the most profit the these
are the fastest growing companies in the
history. Anthropic was a $50 billion
company. It's now a multi-t trillion in
a year and a half. Like you can't fade
what's gone on. Do I think they're going
to get to a trillion dollars in revenue?
Absolutely not. But do I think people
are underestimating what the
biotech companies want to use? What the
nanotechnology companies want to use?
What the everything in the physical
science will pay for frontier
intelligence? You're crazy if you think
they're going to use cheaper models.
Like in the hedge fund industry where
I'm from, this has already happened.
Like Jane Street, Millennium, they're
all using Anthropic. So, everyone's
crazy. But, but here's my thing is
today's episode is brought to you by
Figure Markets. All right, everyone. Who
wants a slice of $160,000?
Our partner figures running a promo
where they're giving back to their
community. from July 27th to August
27th. Any user who has never completed a
cryptoback loan with them can qualify
for this giveaway. Check out the link in
my bio for more information. We're
living in a world of higher for longer
rates, tighter credit, and fewer places
to earn real yield. That's why Figure is
interesting. Figure is the largest
non-bank heliloc lender in the United
States with over $22 billion unlocked
for homeowners. They're now applying
that same concept and innovation to
cryptoback loans and realworld asset
yield. If you're holding crypto, Figure
let you borrow against it at 8.91%
interest, which is 9.999%
APR [music] with a 50% loan to value,
giving you liquidity without selling,
without triggering taxes, and without
stepping out of the market. They use a
decentralized NPC custody, so assets
stay in segregated wallets, protected
from rugps, and they've introduced
liquidation protection to help manage
downside volatility. [music]
And for investors looking for yield,
Democratized Prime offers up to 9% APY
paid hourly backed by realworld private
credit, real cash flows, and not
speculative token emissions. Figure is
building a new capital market on
blockchain, and now you have access to
the upside. Check them out using the
link below. I'm going to argue that I
don't know if Frontier Intelligence is
the actual right label for Open
Anthropic anymore. And I'll give you let
me give you two examples.
I think everyone starts with I want to
use AI. I think AI could be valuable.
And so what you do is you outsource to
what is the smartest thing I could use
that's kind of off the shelf. And you go
right to these guys.
>> There is no way in hell that at Sylvia
with less than 10 people on an
engineering team. We are able to build
better models that are more accurate
than these trillion dollar companies for
personal finance. and Jane Street can't
figure out how to build a better model
for their specific use case in terms of
custom AI harnesses, data pipelines, all
the model weights and and the training
etc. And so what I think and again this
is where uh we are now entering a world
of uh I call jordy thinking
probabilistic thinking
>> of I can't say this with 100% truth but
I know there's not zero
>> I think that open anthropic for many
businesses are the perfect on-ramp so
you get this acceleration on a per
customer basis and then the customer
start to say well can we get better
intelligence can we get cheaper
intelligence they start to try to
optimize that optimization point almost
every CEO I talked to the private market
is saying we are starting to do this
internally. And so to me, what that
means is their future growth is about
how do we go get more of the people who
do not currently use AI to get onboarded
because they're almost like leaking
their existing users. The per token
usage is going down. So they have to go
get new customers to replace the like
leakage or the like retention almost to
some degree. Does that make sense?
>> Yeah. But this gets back into I the part
I disagree with is for everything that
you've said if I told you the most
important point is that we're in the 1%
>> right now of usage
>> and that Jevans paradox is a real thing
which I completely agree with. There's
no way that open AI and anthropic don't
continue to grow. So there's a
difference between growing as fast as
they did for the early inception and
continuing to grow. As someone who
>> I'm not saying they're not going to
grow, by the way. I I agree that they're
going to keep growing. It's just the
nuance dynamics now agree
>> are changing because you also have like
Jev
>> right shows up like like there there's a
lot of stuff that are happening where uh
you made a comment 3 months ago
>> the easy money and AI is over.
>> Yeah.
>> We are now like I'm fully on board with
that and I think that it's becoming very
obvious you can't just be like the big
model labs get all the money.
>> Correct. And and that part I agree with
the the thing the thing that as a user
and using my son as like an example
we both will crap on Gemini.
>> I don't when the new model comes out
well this is good.
>> It makes mistakes that I have open AI
and claude fix constantly.
>> So I think people that use it all the
time and that are scared of mistakes and
hallucinations and things like that know
the models that are more likely to do
this. I think when you make the decision
to go to open source and you go to these
I I personally believe on my own
experience, it better be for stuff that
isn't super important. That's why I
brought up the Jane Street and
Millennium. I don't agree that all these
models are even close to the same. I've
used I I stopped my uh Open Claw and my
Hermes because I was able to do things
in Claude and Anthropic that or in in
Claude and Open AI which were different.
And then when Grockot came out and Muse
came out and everything else, Muse is
not as good a model anything close to
what open but it doesn't need to be.
It's just doing basic stuff for me. So I
think we're saying the same thing. I
just think we agree on this.
>> I think the hardest thing for people to
understand and the most important thing
that I want to get across to people,
you've heard Jeb's paradox.
We're at that point right now. What
happened the last two months may have
been a air pocket on one way which is
this token cost thing but we're entering
a very very dangerous period now for the
next year.
>> The usage is going to skyrocket and we
don't have enough compute.
>> So this gets back to the other thing
OpenAI and Anthropic own.
I listened to the interview with the
instinct founder.
>> Did you listen to it?
>> Yeah. Noah on uh invest like the best.
Yeah. He specifically highlighted that
he underestimated his compute needs.
>> He said, I think he said 40% of his time
is being spent trying to accumulate
compute and he's having a hard time
because he's growing 10% per day. And so
he's like, "How do I project out? If I
double my compute, you know, I basically
use it all up in a couple weeks and then
how do I kind of project how much I'm
going to need?"
>> So here's the scary thing. We're
entering the hype the the the parabola
of efficiency and compute as well with
Vera Rubin. So Blackwells were great.
You the efficiency of the chips. Well,
now we're getting the Vera Rubin. Who
owns all of that? The big guys do.
>> I mean, it's the speculation between
semi analysis and what I've heard on the
all in pod is that open anthropic
combined will own up to 50% of all the
compute coming online. I mean, isn't
that a monopoly or a duopoly of some
sort on compute? And so, this is where I
I don't think you can make the
assumptions that they won't actually go
up again sometime next year just because
they have the compute, which means two
things. Number one, they can service
more people uh more companies. And
number two, their models start getting
better and better because you need more
computing power to actually get to the
level of the IQ that they eventually
want to get to for the physical
sciences.
So um
let's talk about the personal agents
maybe as a uh an area where I think
tokens are going to continue to expand.
We now have just this past week um Robin
Hood announced a bunch of agentic
trading. We have uh OpenAI launched
dots. We have uh Ryan Sirant launched an
AI agent within his simple app which
again is like a very applied AI type
thing. We have Muse, which was already
out, but now is going after small
business.
>> We have uh Noah, the founder of
Instinct, who's basically come out and
said they're doing over a billion
dollars of transactions, 40% I think
it's on travel, that gave a bunch of
numbers in terms of what how what's
going on, how they're doing it, growing
10% day overday. Uh with Sylvia, we
announced now you can text it in a more
agentic way, then have to go into a
archaic dashboard and use it that way.
And then I don't I've lost count. I we
would spend an hour of me rattling off
every single product launch that I saw
from some net new agent that got
released, including I don't know if you
saw this one. There is one I don't want
to say the name because I don't know how
legit it is that you can start with the
agent as a baby and raise it. [snorts]
>> I I haven't heard this
>> launch video was awesome. Looked cool.
Hilarious. I'm sure they've got some
pitch as to why that's better, but like
we're we're [laughter]
we're in banana land a little bit on the
AI agents already. How are you
evaluating personal agents? What are you
using? And where do you think, you know,
is there consolidation or like are you
going to have 20 agents across 20
different use cases?
>> Okay, so there's two parts to this and I
want to make sure the second part
everyone hears first um in terms of you
getting back to it.
Every day since I put Muse on my phone,
I have bought more and more crypto every
single day.
>> Because Muse told you or because you
just become more convinced that
>> because this to me, so I I people have
watched this together now for a while.
Last year when I was frustrated by just
like listening to people not understand
the Micron story about token growth,
the agent stuff with Muse and all of
this, it just blows me away every day
with more things that I can do with it.
And
so let me answer that part. I want to
get to the crypto connection because I
think if anyone should be demanding from
their Fidelity, their Robin Hood,
everything that they have the ability of
at least thinking about this. I really
do believe that we're entering something
that is just breathtaking
cryptoconnected
to agents. So on the agent side, it
started with Grockbot and that was a
game changer for me. Now I use Grockbot
more for the work stuff. I have one
chief of staff who I go to when I want
to have a meeting with the agents or I
want to send off the agents. But
underneath that chief of staff, I now
have two middle management chief of
staff.
>> Uh-oh. Middle managers. Middle managers.
Hey, pull up a chair. Let me tell you
about automation. So I have one for AI,
>> man. You capitalist pig. You going after
the middle managers. Too much time in
Morgan Stanley. So one one side is uh
has got a an AI side. The other side has
a crypto side. And I send them out to
keep up on what's going on.
What Muse did for me. And I think this
is what people need to hear when they go
Meta won. Meta didn't win anything. It's
not even like there's there's [snorts]
going to be so many personal AI and
that's the big thing and that's why it
matters so much is that when Apple comes
out we're going to have a ton. And who
do I think is going to be better at
security? Apple or Meta. I'm I'm going
to go with Apple. It's just my my guess.
But regardless of that, Muse and all of
them, if you haven't used them yet,
I think you're missing the same way that
when we talked about not understanding
tokens, you're going to miss out on some
activity to invest. I think with agents
that my brain only goes one place which
is there's no way for the current system
to handle the speed and the ability to
do things like this. It's just
impossible. And I will give you one
important thought process on this. So
we've heard about agent swarms. So let's
take the two parts of agents. The reason
there's agent swarms now is the same
reason that we have personal agents. We
couldn't have personal agents unless we
got to the point where we had agent
swarms. Because at the end of the day,
that's kind of what you're doing. You
need to have enough IQ to be able to do
all these different tasks, have the
memory, have it, and agent swarms have
the same thing. The reason this is
important, the current system, when you
go to wire money to someone, if you go
to wire money to someone on a Friday at
3:00, it'll settle on Monday. Where's
your money for the last two days?
Where's it sitting? And I challenge
anyone to actually know where their
money is when they use a credit card to
go buy something and it goes from your
bank account to the merchant through the
credit card. I keep hearing people tell
me, "Well, Vis and Mastercard are going
to be the winners in this." I'm like,
"No, they're not. They have no chance. I
I don't even know where this comes
from." And this argument comes up all
the time. the amount of steps between
buying something and settling something.
The longer it takes, even if it's 20
seconds versus one second, that's
multiple times for an agent swarm to
come in and steal the money along. You
need every single part of it. So, you
remember the cold wallet story, right?
[snorts]
Crypto is based on cryptography. Like,
this is going to be a necessity to make
sure that it's instant cuz that is the
best defense on anything. If you're
worried about someone robbing your
house, but they will only rob it when
you're not there, well, the best thing
would be to go outside for a second,
come back in. The longer you leave, you
go on vacation, the higher the
probability. I think people need to
start understanding that the the the
lineup of cryptography to AIS is not
just about them wanting to do things
fast. It's not just the cost. It is also
the time of risk against agent swarms.
And I think that's going to become more
of a story. This is the reason why every
time I use it, I'm like, "Oh my gosh,
this is so obvious that number one,
we didn't need crypto. We didn't need
the tokens. We didn't need the altcoins.
We needed the layer ones to kind of draw
capital in to build out the
infrastructure that was necessary. So,
when you have the L1's growing and
continuing to get bigger and bigger,
well, that means the ecosystem is
getting bigger. And as Michael Sailor
says, the capital structure can now
change because we actually have digital
collateral. We have Bitcoin. We have
Ethereum. So we have the programmable
side but you need that thing that
actually makes it well this is the use
case and I said the same thing if you go
back and look when Uber started Uber
didn't start as a company in terms of
the idea until the app store happened
then they went oh we can do this so I
think you're going to see innovation
after innovation related to this so what
I have spent my time on as someone who
listens to so many podcasts a week
[snorts] very seldom now do I listen to
moonshots very seldom do I into any of
these in
>> they've been dominated by crypto now and
not rah hoodie crypto I mean the
functional use cases and different ways
to value these because I am getting
constantly I mean this has happened
three times this week calls with hedge
fund and ass and asset man let's just
say asset managers
tell me about why I should be investing
in crypto
These conversations never existed. When
you and I talked, you gave me all the
horror stories of walking into rooms.
>> They are asking you in terms of I hear
you talking about crypto and I disagree
so convince me or they are saying I am
interested. Help me better understand
you know where to put the money that I
want to invest.
>> Yeah. The best analogy is um the door
was closed and you had to pry it open.
>> They're looking through the door.
>> I see. they they're they're interested
and the reason is and this is the
>> this is the Wall Street FOMO building
up.
>> I I don't I so I think it is coming from
from two directions. One is every day
Goldman Sachs, Morgan Stanley, City
Bank, they're all involved in it. All of
them. They're racing for tokenization.
They're racing for stable coins and
that's the key thing. But then there's
another argument which is
the connection of agents to crypto makes
sense. Like that's the whole point is
that there's an element of oh this makes
sense. And the reason I'm so emphatic
and pounding the table that this is so
important
>> is and I don't I don't know how to
pronounce Ilia's last name from near
>> but if you go back and listen to an
interview with him in 2023 on a podcast
called No Priors
>> great podcast
>> great podcast and but this was a very
futuristic look of where we are today.
So in 2023 if I said to you okay he did
this interview it was only 6 months
after
Gen AI started chatbt was launched how
could a guy have this much vision on the
agentic world connecting to it literally
that's what near that's what he was
talking about how could he have that
vision because he was one of the
co-authors on the transformer paper that
led to generative AI so there's two
things about that so I'm a logical guy
like I I look at things and go I like
listening to this guy this is great
his value as one of the transformer page
co-authors when AI took over and people
were paying hundreds of millions if not
billions of dollars for humans. You
don't think Ilia got a call and could
have left near and gone there but he
believes in this there there's a lot of
elements for me as like a founder that I
like listening to and getting to know
the people. So I think if people go back
and listen to that, forget investing in
NER. Just go listen to the story and go
listen to someone who believes agents
have to be part of crypto back in so
this was also when crypto was on its way
down everything was breaking down. He
was saying when agents are here that's
when the connection will be. And
literally what he said is they will be
the economic actors of the future. And
so that's why every day that I sit there
I'm like oh I know what's happening now.
And so if I get off the call, and this
happened to me once this week, I'm
meeting someone for breakfast coming up
soon,
has two portfolios, follows me in AI,
he's a subscriber, he's been doing well,
and he's got all these names, but then
at the same point, he's got a lot of
crypto, which he told me about. He's
like, I don't need any more crypto. I
still have stuff from 2021 and 2022. And
that was an interesting thing because I
remember hearing that after the do
bubble. All the people that I knew that
bought a lot of these things, they
didn't put more money into it because
they still had PTSD from what they went
through. I think there's a a period here
where the asset managers are looking to
invest. I think most of what's driving
crypto right now is a combination of new
players coming in. This is what a bull
market is about. And you're right, FOMO
is going to start to kick in very, very
soon. I said before when Bitcoin got
above 82,000, that was the confirmation
of the bull trend. I think we're in
that. The fundamental side's getting
stronger and stronger by the day. I I
think we're at a point where this stuff
is about to kind of take off,
particularly with what happened today
with the unemployment rate being lower
than expected. If you take everything
that happened this week from the rate
picture and you look at it and you're
like, David Zervos brought into the Fed
or brought into the Treasury, he wants
he's he's a very creative guy. Uh we're
going to he's he's being brought in to
help get long-term rates lower. They did
another buyback, another, you know,
treasury uh yield curve, treasury uh
twitch, whatever you want to call it in
terms of the twisting of the back end
versus the front end. We got a lower
than expected PCE core. Now we got an
unemployment number that came in weaker
than expected with an hourly earnings
that came in weaker than expected. So
maybe rates settle here. They don't have
to go down, guys. They just need to not
be a story where every day they go up.
And I think we could be staring at a a
position coming out of the midterms
where people are like, "Why were we
waiting? Earnings are just growing
rapidly and we're entering earning
season in two weeks." Today's episode is
brought to you by Galaxy 1. A lot of
people got their money working for them.
But the question now, how hard is it
working? Well, the folks over at Galaxy
1, they're taking a very different
approach. Everyone earns 3.5% APY using
Galaxy 1 Cash. And if you make over
$200,000 a year, that means you're
probably an accredited investor. And
then you can earn up to 8% on your cash
guaranteed by Galaxy Digital. The best
part though is that you can actually set
it so that your yield immediately is
reinvested into your favorite stocks,
crypto, or ETFs. You don't got to think
about it every single month. It just
automatically does it for you. That's
why I love Galaxy 1. So, if your cash
isn't working as hard as you are, then
it's time to make a move. Check out the
link in the description and start
earning today. This episode is brought
to you by Lava. The Lava card is the
first credit card that allows you to
earn up to 5% back in Bitcoin on every
single purchase. Most cards have steep
annual fees and unclear points programs,
but the Lava card offers a much better
deal. Earn real Bitcoin every time that
you spend. Plus, there's no annual fee.
There's zero FX fees and zero spread
when you spend internationally. On top
of that, Lava gives you access to a
Bitcoin line of credit, yield on cash,
instant stable coin deposits and
withdrawals, on and off ramps to and
from your bank account, and much, much
more. With Lava, you can borrow against
your Bitcoin at the lowest rates, earn
yield, move money globally, and stack
Bitcoin with each and every purchase you
make. Most financial services squeeze
you with high fees, confusing rewards
programs. Lava keeps it simple, and they
help you build your long-term savings
via your everyday spend. Visit lava.xyz
xyz/pmp
to get started in just a few minutes
today. lava.xyzp
to get started today.
>> You ever gone to a high school football
game
>> many times
>> and uh you see the the young men on the
sidelines, fourth quarter comes, they
start holding up the four fingers like
this.
>> Y
>> you don't know this, but the uh the OG
podcast viewers, every fourth quarter we
go like this. You know why?
>> Why?
>> Cuz crypto loves the fourth quarter. It
loves it. Like just like the high school
football team's like, "We win the fourth
quarter." Krypto's like, "We win the
fourth quarter." It's October 3rd. You
know, like you ever seen a bull right
before he stampedes, he kind of digs his
feet into the ground, throws up some
dust. October 3rd. That's what the bulls
do. [laughter]
>> And then it's fourth quarter. Like here
we go. I think it was over the summer
that when it first when we had the seven
sigma move that I reminded both the
audience and you that the viewpoint for
this year was that based on the work
being done by institutional investors
that when we came to the end of the year
something very important happened. So
this will match up with your fourth
quarter thing but I think this one's the
most important. It's for important for
people to hear. This is my mindset.
>> Jord is unbothered. He's just like get
out of here with this fourth quarter
course. Just give us a four.
four year cycle I don't care about and
this I don't care about but I do know
this
>> large allocators and decision makers
make really important decisions for the
following calendar year
>> in the fourth quarter
>> in the fourth quarter and the reason
that's important and particularly in the
final two months
they get paid on performance which
crystallizes sometime around that end of
the you know and into the beginning of
the year
>> oh there's somebody out there they're up
big right now they're selling and
they're not going to touch their
portfolio till December Exactly. And so
if you want to get involved with crypto,
they're doing their homework. The
problem they're running into, I've been
asked this many times. So what can I
buy? And I go, well, you can either buy
buy the, you know, the ETFs or the, you
know, the DATs of the various ones or
maybe there's five companies you public
stocks you can buy.
>> It's really hard, but they want to do
it. So, I think that's where the L1
start to become, you know, a
>> they're not going to drive things, but
they're there's going to be an
underlying bid for these things that
keeps the ecosystem grounded. And that
means that the beta is going to continue
to show up in the altcoins, but the beta
is going to be driven not by the
institutional managers until the
tokenization starts to happen. That's
why tokenization is so important.
>> So, there's two uh two data points that
I will uh I will share. Um, I think back
in May or June, I tweeted much to the uh
uh disappointment of all the AI bulls
and I said it's going to be glorious
when the AI profits rotate back into
Bitcoin and I was trolling a little bit,
but I do believe that, you know, a lot
of the crypto gains went into AI, people
continue, you got the momentum and now
you're going to kind of see this
rotation back. Um, it does feel like
that's starting to happen a little bit.
To your point, I don't think that the
interest in AI is going away. I just
think that people are becoming a little
bit more interested in Bitcoin and
crypto. So now you kind of have these
two technologies.
>> The second thing, uh, I am shocked right
now. I believe Sylvia is the only public
company that has AI and Bitcoin kind of
married together. It's a it's a little
bit of a weird way that we've done it.
>> Y,
>> I am very very shocked that maybe the
only ones you could assign to are like a
Coinbase or like a Robin Hood who have
like crypto products and then they're
like using AI, you know, in some form or
fashion. But I feel like this is
becoming somewhat of a more consensus
view that these two technologies are
going to benefit from each other and
it's going to be there. One of my
predictions for 2027 is you're going to
start to see an assault of public
markets where people they may be an AI,
you know, related business. They're
going to start trying to do crypto
stuff. Crypto will do more AI.
>> And so I think what investors are going
to have to try to figure out is like
where does the value acrew, right? So if
you look at take maybe Coinbase and
Robin Hood, Coinbase came from the
crypto world, Robin Hood comes from the
brokerage world. they kind of have ended
up in this like, you know, war over
who's going to be like the everything
exchange. Both great businesses. I think
both will do very well going forward,
but they have kind of like the DNA of
the company is a little bit different.
And so if you were like, hey, I want to
be more like 7030 crypto to AI, you
probably would go and buy a Coinbase. If
you want to be like 7030, you know,
equities, then or AI, you'd go to like
more Robin Hood.
>> That I think is actually much harder for
people to navigate. Again, going back to
this like all the easy money's gone.
>> Yep. If you're an institutional
allocator and you're like, "Okay, cool.
I believe in everything Jord's saying.
Where do I go put my money,
>> you're now almost getting like the the
more intricate decisions?" And so, one,
I think that uh similar to how we talked
about like lawyers, advice will become
more valuable than the action of just
like filling out the documents.
>> Your philosophy is going to become
consensus. And now it is going to become
much more about like what are the
specific names? How do I think about
portfolio construction? How do I think
about onetime purchase versus dollar
cost averaging? I mean, like very
specific, you know, kind of tactical
things.
>> This is where uh so I'm and you and I
haven't talked about this, but I'll I'll
I'll bring in. So, because I have
subscribers that want to invest in the
46 name index that I created, they want
to
>> around tokenization.
>> Yeah. Well, it Yeah. Around it's really
the crypto ecosystem. So, this is
really, hey, agents are going to do
things. Okay. This is the entire
ecosystem that should benefit. And
rather than you go out and pick five
tokens, I think the beauty of the way I
put it together is equal weight. It's
got the L1's and then it's got a bunch
of L2s, 46 names. Just uh you're not
allowed to say this, but I have a uh
report here. Um let me look to make sure
I got this right. The Visceral Labs 46
name index, which by the way, we got to
get you a better name. [laughter] Visor
Labs.
It's like uh you know for for whatever
people say about Trump good or bad the
guy's good at branding and super
intelligence probably is a better name.
The Visser Labs 46 name index is up year
to date 50%. Bitcoin is down 3.2% as of
the close yesterday.
>> So that I think gives a a pretty clear
this is outperforming Bitcoin as a
benchmark.
>> And if you would have looked the prior
year or you know when Bitcoin peaked,
Bitcoin was outperforming and all of the
altcoins were were underperforming.
That's what makes this so important. It
ties it back to AI. What I was going to
say is I'm reaching out now to asset
managers. So, anyone out there who's
doing anything. I ran ETFs
>> if you breathe.
>> I ran ETFs at Morgan Stanley. I traded
programs. I traded derivatives. The
future is to give both individual
investors and asset managers what
they're going to be able to do within a
year, which is some kind of tokenized
way to do this agentically. This
compares So, I'm going to set this up
myself. I'm going to do this. Um, I'm
also going to connect to API keys to be
able to do the research on crypto. At
this point, you should be able to turn
everything into an investment dashboard
that has the 46 name index. You trade it
with a push of a button with agents. I'm
going to do that on my own and I'm going
to set it up. And I don't know if Robin
Hood can do it yet. I don't know if
Coinbase can do it yet. But anyone else
out there, um, I reached out to Bill
Barte. I'm I'm reaching out. anyone
wants to come to me and work with me on
this. I don't want to launch an ETF, but
I do want my subscribers to have the
ability of investing that way because
that's the way the future is going to
be. An agent can go out and do all 46
names, equal weight the whole thing, and
then you have it done within seconds.
We're at that point where it should be
able to get done. The only nuance is
there's 42
tokens and then there's four public
stocks. So, in the world of the merging
of tokenization,
it's a race to see who can handle Jord's
portfolio first. [snorts]
>> Um, I like this idea. I do think this is
where the world is going. Uh, I do not
think it will happen as fast as everyone
claims it will. And um I will uh
introduce you to uh a couple lawyers uh
because as we've gone down this path um
>> there are a lot of very antiquated rules
around how they will empower this to
happen.
>> And so uh I'm an investor in a company
called Autopilot. They do something
similar different but but similar. I
think they've done a great job. Um you
now are seeing the agentic trading e
Toro, Robin Hood, Coinbase like they're
all going into that. Um, public has this
like describe something and it will then
create an index for you kind of a custom
index. Um, I think maybe you can kind of
trade off of it um in the product. Super
take we we recently talked about in
terms of like you know I think snow's
going to snow a lot in the mountain like
how do I invest along that theme? Like
this is definitely where the world is
headed.
>> What I think is maybe most interesting
is twofold. Creating it and putting it
on easy. how do people sell or rotate or
that type of stuff I think is we just
need to figure it out. I don't think
people have really spent a lot of time
there.
>> And then the second thing is um the
rules have to catch up with this type of
investing because the rules are frankly
situated for ETFs, mutual funds, like
that stuff. This is the future.
But like if I said to you, hey, you got
to go become an RA to do this. You
probably would be like, eh, I'm not
interested. I don't know if you have to,
right? But the platforms for sure, if
they're going to empower this stuff,
there are legal things that they need to
do. We're entering a weird world where
like if the agents are doing the
trading, like are the agents regulated?
You know, one of the things I've always
talked about is uh in crypto back in the
day, uh there's certain things that
exchanges have to file with the SEC.
Well, if it's decentralized,
how does it file? And then like also how
do you enforce the rules? So
decentralization for exchanges is an
interesting thing because regulators
weren't like you're not even trying to
be malicious just like how do we
interface with each other.
I think this is now coming in a weird
way. What you're talking about is almost
like a decentralized ETF.
How do how does the regulators how do
the rules interface?
>> I don't think they have an answer yet.
They're they're trying to figure it out
but they don't have an answer.
>> So here's what's going to happen a year
from now. And I keep saying a year from
now because my mindset is that we are at
the micron moment as I call it where
people just underestimate how fast this
stuff goes. And if I'm right, uh,
every wealth advisor,
every uh, wealth management firm is
going to be in a very very difficult
position a year from now.
their clients are going to start hearing
about how people are making a lot of
money in crypto and they're going to
hear crypto and rather than crypto I
want everyone to just think they're
making money in tokens
well stocks are going to be tokenized
for sure now will they be the same way
there's going to be a merging here but
if people go well I I heard you know I
heard Joe and Mary just made 30 times
their money over here this is the weird
part about if I'm right about what's
happening and you have to Go back to the
Micron example. Never in my time have I
seen what I saw with my agentic
portfolio infrastructure, which is I
thought Micron would double. I thought
it might triple 14 times. Now that was
totally based on the earnings growth.
>> I see the crypto volumes, the token
volumes going through the roof because
of tokenization and because of stable
coin payments,
>> because of AI agents. If it wasn't for
agents, which will speed this process up
to make it easier, I wouldn't be as
optimistic on it. So, it started now and
I think everyone listening who watches
us regularly of which we have a goodiz
audience. This is a problem you want to
be ahead of both as an in personal
investor, you want to start doing your
research. This weekend when I go
through, I will do another video on
crypto plus my regular weekly video. I
am going to highlight seven separate
podcasts. I not only spoke to Ilyia at
near I spoke to William Mgayar who
you've had on he was amazing brilliant
brilliant guy he's got a new book coming
out it's going to take another 3 to 6
months I think for his book to come out
you have to be on top of these guys
Joseph Chalam or Shalom who was at
BlackRock
>> all over it
they're all over it and they're telling
you why to invest in it and they're
telling you why this moment matters now
and a lot of it has to do with the
regulatory side but most of it has to do
with the three of them saw this vision a
long time ago playing out and they're
all respectable people with different
backgrounds. One traditional Wall
Street, one Napster, one uh uh Google.
Seriously, I mean, when I get a
diversity of people that are very, very
bright, and I'm going to be putting six
podcasts from the three of them up this
weekend, you got to go watch this stuff
and be on top of it. Ladies and
gentlemen, that's it. I appreciate all
of you guys watching. We got a lot of
new people who've been watching this
lately. We appreciate you. Make sure you
subscribe to the channel, tell your
friends, text us to somebody, leave a
funny comment for Jordy. The funniest
ones to actually screenshot and send to
him sometimes. It makes him laugh, think
that we're all smart over here. Uh, make
sure you go to YouTube, check out Jordy
Visser. Just type in Jordy Visser. Jordy
with an I. And hit subscribe there.
That's the digital thank you to him
doing such a great job every single
week. And then go and check out Sylvia.
Go to sylvia.com. Silvia.com if you want
to use AI to better manage your finances
and your portfolio. We've got a very
interesting announcement coming out on
Monday. Just a little alpha for all of
you.